Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
Welcome back everyone.
欢迎大家回来。
So, what are we talking about today, Marco?
那么，Marco，我们今天要聊什么？
We are going to the flower shop.
我们要去花店。
Okay, so this is an intermediate level lesson and we're going to be learning about the different
好的，这是一节中级课程，我们将学习关于
kinds of flowers you can buy at a flower shop.
在花店里可以买到的各种花。
And so, we've got a guy here who's probably trying to say something to someone he loves.
我们这里有个家伙，他大概想对心爱的人说些什么。
Yeah, I think he did something to his girlfriend or wife.
是啊，我觉得他对他女朋友或老婆做了什么错事。
And well, that's the typical thing, right?
嗯，这是典型的情况，对吧？
You do something wrong, so you got to get her flowers.
你做了错事，就得给她买花。
And that's why women are often very nervous when their husband or boyfriend gives them
这就是为什么女人在丈夫或男朋友送花时常常很紧张，
flowers because she's thinking, hmm, what did he do wrong?
因为她会想，嗯，他做错了什么？
All right, so let's listen to the dialogue and we'll be back soon.
好了，我们来听对话，一会儿再回来。
Hello, sir.
你好，先生。
How may I help you?
有什么可以帮您的？
I would like to buy some flowers, please.
我想买些花。
Something really nice.
要特别漂亮的。
I see.
我明白了。
May I ask what the occasion is?
请问是什么场合？
It's not really an occasion.
其实不是什么场合。
It's more like I'm sorry.
更像是道歉。
Very well.
很好。
This arrangement here is very popular among regretful husbands and boyfriends.
这里的这个花束在后悔的丈夫和男朋友中很受欢迎。
It has a dozen long stem red roses with a couple of sunflowers and a single orchid that
它包含一打长茎红玫瑰，配上几朵向日葵和一朵
stands out.
突出的兰花。
It includes a small teddy bear to achieve the effect of immediate forgiveness.
还附带一个小泰迪熊，以达到立即被原谅的效果。
I think I'm going to need more than just a dozen red roses and a bear.
我想我需要的不仅仅是一打红玫瑰和一只熊。
What else do you recommend?
你还有什么推荐？
Hmm, well, this is our I'm sorry I cheated on you package.
嗯，这是我们的“对不起我出轨了”套餐。
Two dozen red roses lined with tulips, carnations and lilies.
两打红玫瑰，配上郁金香、康乃馨和百合。
The fragrance and beauty of this flower arrangement is sure to make her forgive you.
这束花的芬芳和美丽一定能让她原谅你。
I don't think that's going to cut it.
我觉得这还不够。
I need something bigger and better.
我需要更大更好的。
I'm sorry, sir, but what exactly did you do?
对不起，先生，你到底做了什么？
Well, I may have accidentally insinuated that she is getting chubbier.
嗯，我可能不小心暗示她变胖了。
Get out of my store, you jerk.
滚出我的店，你这个混蛋。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So what do you think?
你觉得怎么样？
Is this really like a bad thing to do?
这真的是一件很糟糕的事吗？
Heck yeah.
当然啦。
No, really?
不会吧？
Well, no one wants to hear that someone thinks they're fat.
嗯，没人想听别人说自己胖。
Okay, and chubby is maybe not as bad as fat, but the guy could have been a little bit nicer.
好吧，“chubby”可能没有“fat”那么糟糕，但这家伙本可以更委婉一点。
All right, so we'll give our listeners some advice towards the end of the lesson.
好了，我们会在课程快结束时给听众一些建议。
So now why don't we take a look at all the flower names in Language Takeaway.
现在，我们来看看“语言要点”里的所有花名。
Language Takeaway
语言要点
Okay, this first flower is a beautiful one and it has delicious seeds that people like
好的，第一种花很漂亮，它的种子很好吃，
to eat.
人们喜欢吃。
It's called a sunflower.
它叫向日葵。
A sunflower.
向日葵。
All right, so that's a yellow flower, right?
好的，那是一种黄色的花，对吧？
It's bright yellow and in the middle is orange and the stems are very, very long.
它是亮黄色的，中间是橙色的，茎非常非常长。
And thick.
而且很粗。
Yeah, and thick.
对，而且很粗。
So it's a tall flower.
所以它是一种高大的花。
Okay, sunflower.
好的，向日葵。
And yeah, as you mentioned, some people eat sunflower seeds.
是的，就像你提到的，有些人吃葵花籽。
They're like the little salty ones, right?
它们是那种小小的咸味瓜子，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
They're really good.
它们真的很好吃。
All right, next is an orchid.
好的，下一种是兰花。
Okay, an orchid is a beautiful flower and they're often grown just one at a time and
好的，兰花是一种美丽的花，通常一次只长一朵，
people collect orchids.
人们会收集兰花。
So these can be very, very expensive.
所以它们可能非常非常贵。
They're very expensive.
它们非常贵。
And they come in all shapes, sizes and colors.
而且它们有各种形状、大小和颜色。
Okay, an orchid.
好的，兰花。
Now what about a tulip?
那郁金香呢？
A tulip is another pretty flower and I think they're most famous in Holland for their tulips
郁金香是另一种漂亮的花，我觉得荷兰的郁金香最有名，
because this actually used to be the kind of money that they would use.
因为这种花曾经被当作货币使用。
This was their currency for many years.
它们曾是很多年的货币。
So they used to use tulips.
所以他们过去用郁金香。
They used to use tulips and the tulip flower is kind of like a, it's like a champagne glass.
他们过去用郁金香，郁金香花有点像香槟杯的形状。
It's tall and it's kind of empty in the middle.
它很高，中间有点空。
Oh, that's interesting.
哦，真有趣。
So next time somebody says, do you think money grows on trees?
所以下次有人说，你觉得钱能长在树上吗？
In Holland it literally did.
在荷兰，它确实长在树上。
Well, yeah.
嗯，是啊。
Almost.
差不多。
All right, what about a carnation?
好的，那康乃馨呢？
Okay, a carnation is another pretty flower and they come, I think, in red, pink and white.
好的，康乃馨是另一种漂亮的花，我觉得有红色、粉色和白色。
Yeah, I've mostly seen white carnations.
是的，我大多见过白色康乃馨。
Yeah.
嗯。
And, you know, flower giving, there's a whole definition to it, right?
而且，你知道，送花有很多讲究，对吧？
So yeah, every flower is symbolic of something.
是的，每种花都有象征意义。
Red roses are for love and carnations, I think, are generally for either friendship or like
红玫瑰代表爱情，而康乃馨，我觉得通常代表友谊或者
when someone died, I'm not sure.
有人去世时用，我不太确定。
You can give them to somebody who's passed away.
你可以送给去世的人。
Really?
真的吗？
I'm not sure.
我不确定。
I'll have to look it up.
我得查查。
But carnation is another very, very common flower that you'll see in many different colors.
但康乃馨是另一种非常常见的花，有各种颜色。
Okay.
好的。
And a flower is also really common.
还有一种花也很常见。
It's a lily.
是百合。
All right.
好的。
A lily is a beautiful flower and usually you see these on water.
百合是一种美丽的花，通常你会在水面上看到它们。
So water lilies, for example, is another name you might hear.
所以“水百合”是另一个你可能听到的名字。
Okay.
好的。
A water lily or just a regular lily.
水百合或者普通的百合。
And next we have the most common of all the flowers, but we've added a little twist to
接下来是最常见的一种花，但我们给它加了点花样。
it.
It's a long stem rose.
它是长茎玫瑰。
Right.
对。
So rose, everyone knows.
所以玫瑰，大家都知道。
A rose by any other name would smell as sweet.
玫瑰换个名字也一样芬芳。
Shakespeare wrote a lot about roses.
莎士比亚写了很多关于玫瑰的诗。
But in this case, we're talking about long stem roses.
但这里，我们说的是长茎玫瑰。
And we talked about this with sunflowers.
我们之前聊向日葵时也提到过。
The stem is the green part that grows out of the ground and you think of the flower
茎是从地里长出来的绿色部分，你可以把花看作头。
as the head.
And so the stem is actually the connector between the ground and the flower.
所以茎实际上是连接地面和花的部位。
Okay.
好的。
So these types of roses have a really long stem.
所以这种玫瑰的茎特别长。
So they're very nice to like maybe give one of them away.
所以它们很适合比如送一朵给别人。
That's right.
没错。
And you see, for example, at the opera, you see singers, people throw these roses at them
而且你看，比如在歌剧院，歌手表演时，人们会把这些玫瑰扔给他们。
and they pick them up and they're so long, the stems are so long and they collect them
他们捡起花，花茎很长，他们收集起来
in their arms.
抱在怀里。
And so that's a long stem rose.
所以那就是长茎玫瑰。
All right.
好的。
Interesting.
有意思。
Okay.
嗯。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the second time?
我们再来听一遍对话怎么样？
Let's keep a lookout for these flower names and their pronunciation.
注意听这些花的名字和它们的发音。
And we'll come back in a little bit.
我们一会儿再回来。
Hello, sir.
您好，先生。
How may I help you?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
I would like to buy some flowers, please.
我想买些花。
Something really nice.
要特别漂亮的。
I see.
我明白了。
May I ask what the occasion is?
请问是什么场合？
It's not really an occasion.
其实不算什么场合。
It's more like I'm sorry.
更像是道歉。
Very well.
很好。
This flower arrangement here is very popular among regretful husbands and boyfriends.
这里的这个花束在后悔的丈夫和男朋友中很受欢迎。
It has a dozen long stem red roses with a couple of sunflowers and a single orchid that
它包含一打长茎红玫瑰，几朵向日葵，还有一朵突出的
stands out.
兰花。
It includes a small teddy bear to achieve the effect of immediate forgiveness.
还附带一个小泰迪熊，以达到立即被原谅的效果。
I think I'm going to need more than just a dozen red roses and a bear.
我想我需要的不仅仅是一打红玫瑰和一只熊。
What else do you recommend?
您还有什么推荐的吗？
Well, this is our I'm sorry I cheated on you package.
嗯，这是我们的“对不起我出轨了”套餐。
Two dozen red roses lined with tulips, carnations and lilies.
两打红玫瑰，搭配郁金香、康乃馨和百合。
The fragrance and beauty of this flower arrangement is sure to make her forgive you.
这束花的芬芳和美丽一定能让她原谅你。
I don't think that's going to cut it.
我觉得那还不够。
I need something bigger and better.
我需要更大更好的。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
But what exactly did you do?
但您到底做了什么？
Well, I may have accidentally insinuated that she is getting chubbier.
嗯，我可能不小心暗示她变胖了。
Get out of my store, you jerk.
滚出我的店，你这个混蛋。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So in this dialogue, we had a lot of interesting phrases.
在这段对话中，我们听到了很多有趣的短语。
So let's look at them now in Fluency Builder.
现在我们来看一下“流利度构建”部分。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
A lot of these phrases, Marco, have to do with, well, what the guy did wrong in today's
马可，这些短语很多都和今天对话里那个男人做错的事有关。
dialogue.
And so the first one is to cheat on.
第一个是“出轨”。
So the woman offered him the I'm sorry I cheated on you package, right?
所以那位女士给他推荐了“对不起我出轨了”套餐，对吧？
So it's like an arrangement of flowers that usually people buy when they cheated on their
就是那种通常人们在出轨后买的花束。
boyfriend or girlfriend.
Right.
对。
And so in this case, to cheat on means to see another person.
在这种情况下，“出轨”意思是和别人交往。
So if you're married to a woman, seeing someone else, you know, having a date or romantic
所以如果你娶了一个女人，却和别人约会或发生浪漫关系，
encounter with another person is cheating on your wife.
那就是对你妻子不忠。
So you're cheating on your wife.
所以你是在背叛你的妻子。
Right.
对。
You use it like this.
用法是这样的。
Cheat on, right?
“出轨”，对吧？
Cheat on.
“出轨”。
So he cheated on her or they were both cheating on each other.
所以他背叛了她，或者他们互相背叛。
OK, so to cheat on.
好的，所以“出轨”。
Not a good thing.
不是好事。
All right.
好的。
So he was explaining to her that wasn't enough.
所以他向她解释那不够。
The arrangement wasn't enough.
那个花束不够。
And he said, I don't think that's going to cut it.
他说：“我觉得那不够。”
Well, OK, you've probably heard the word cut before.
嗯，你可能以前听过“cut”这个词。
But in this case, Marco, we're talking about to be able to cut something, cut it.
但在这里，马可，我们说的是“能应付”或“够用”。
So that's not going to cut it or it's not going to cut it.
所以“那不够”或“它不够”。
It's not going to be enough.
它不够好。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's not quite what I'm looking for.
所以那不是我要找的。
It's not enough.
不够。
He wants bigger and better.
他想要更大更好的。
He wants more.
他想要更多。
And so, for example, we could say, you know what?
所以，举个例子，我们可以说：“你知道吗？”
This dessert's not going to cut it.
“这个甜点不够好。”
We need something much fancier.
“我们需要更精致的。”
OK, so to be good enough for.
好的，所以意思是“足够好”。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
And then he was explaining to the shop lady what happened.
然后他向花店女士解释发生了什么。
And he said, well, I accidentally insinuated.
他说：“嗯，我无意中暗示了。”
OK, to insinuate is to suggest.
好的，“暗示”意思是“建议”。
So I could say, hey, you're really chubby.
所以我可以直接说：“嘿，你真的很胖。”
That's not an insinuation.
那不是暗示。
That's a statement.
那是陈述。
But I could say, well, you're looking a little bit round at the sides.
但我可以说：“嗯，你看起来两边有点圆。”
That's an insinuation because I'm suggesting without saying something.
那就是暗示，因为我在不直接说的情况下暗示了。
Right.
对。
So you're saying something indirectly.
所以你是在间接地说。
Exactly.
没错。
And he was insinuating that his girlfriend was getting chubbier.
他暗示他的女朋友变胖了。
Chubby.
“胖乎乎”。
So chubby, chubbier, chubbiest.
所以“胖乎乎”、“更胖”、“最胖”。
In this case, we're talking about being round or a little bit overweight.
在这里，我们说的是圆润或有点超重。
Right.
对。
So it's not really saying fat.
所以不是直接说“胖”。
No, fat is rude.
不，“胖”很粗鲁。
Chubby is, you know, it's in between.
“胖乎乎”是，你知道，介于两者之间。
Just a little bit extra pounds.
只是多了一点体重。
Yeah, like maybe you had a little bit too much ice cream over the past couple months.
是的，就像过去几个月可能冰淇淋吃多了。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll be back.
那我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来。
Hello, sir.
您好，先生。
How may I help you?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
I would like to buy some flowers, please.
我想买些花。
Something really nice.
要特别漂亮的。
I see.
我明白了。
May I ask what the occasion is?
请问是什么场合？
It's not really an occasion.
其实不算什么场合。
It's more like I'm sorry.
更像是道歉。
Very well.
很好。
This flower arrangement here is very popular among regretful husbands and boyfriends.
这里的这个花束在后悔的丈夫和男朋友中很受欢迎。
It has a dozen long stem red roses with a couple of sunflowers and a single orchid that
它包含一打长茎红玫瑰，几朵向日葵，还有一朵突出的
stands out.
兰花。
It includes a small teddy bear to achieve the effect of immediate forgiveness.
还附带一个小泰迪熊，以达到立即被原谅的效果。
I think I'm going to need more than just a dozen red roses and a bear.
我想我需要的不仅仅是一打红玫瑰和一只熊。
What else do you recommend?
您还有什么推荐的吗？
Well, this is our I'm sorry I cheated on you package.
嗯，这是我们的“对不起我出轨了”套餐。
Two dozen red roses lined with tulips, carnations and lilies.
两打红玫瑰，搭配郁金香、康乃馨和百合。
The fragrance and beauty of this flower arrangement is sure to make her forgive you.
这束花的芬芳和美丽一定能让她原谅你。
I don't think that's going to cut it.
我觉得那还不够。
I need something bigger and better.
我需要更大更好的。
I'm sorry, sir, but what exactly did you do?
对不起，先生，但您到底做了什么？
Well, I may have accidentally insinuated that she is getting chubbier.
嗯，我可能不小心暗示她变胖了。
Get out of my store, you jerk.
滚出我的店，你这个混蛋。
All right, so if you make a mistake, like as a guy, right, you give flowers to your
好吧，所以如果你犯了错，比如作为男人，对吧，你会送花给你的
girlfriend.
女朋友。
What about women giving flowers to guys?
那女人送花给男人呢？
Is that common?
这常见吗？
Do you think that's possible?
你觉得这可能吗？
Can you do that?
你能这么做吗？
I'm sure you can do it, but I don't know if it's as common.
我确定你能做，但我不确定是否那么常见。
Like I think as a guy, I wouldn't really feel comfortable receiving flowers.
比如我觉得作为男人，收到花不会太自在。
I mean, I would be touched by the gesture and I would be like, oh, that's really sweet.
我的意思是，我会被这个举动感动，会想，哦，这真的很贴心。
But like flowers, it's a little bit too feminine, I think.
但像花，我觉得有点太女性化了。
Generally, I think it's a one sided thing.
总的来说，我认为这是单向的事情。
So you can get flowers for your mother or you can get flowers for a friend or if someone,
所以你可以送花给你妈妈，或者送花给朋友，或者如果有人
you know, passed away, you can get flowers for their family.
去世了，你可以送花给他们的家人。
But in a romantic situation, rarely do you get flowers to a guy.
但在浪漫情境中，很少会送花给男人。
So if you want to say I'm sorry to a guy, what do you give him?
所以如果你想对男人说对不起，你会送他什么？
Season tickets to his favorite football team.
他最喜欢的足球队的季票。
That works.
这管用。
Or a game for his PlayStation.
或者给他PlayStation的游戏。
A game for his PlayStation or offer him a new coat of paint on his car.
给他PlayStation的游戏，或者给他的车提供一次新喷漆。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Have you never given a gift to somebody like saying I'm sorry?
你从没送过礼物给别人来表示道歉吗？
No.
没有。
No, you don't make mistakes.
不，你从不犯错。
I like to use my words.
我喜欢用言语表达。
That's good.
那很好。
Yeah, this is kind of interesting.
是啊，这挺有意思的。
Why do we do this?
我们为什么要这么做？
So why do we give gifts to people as a token or as a demonstration of our regretfulness?
所以我们为什么要送礼物给别人，作为我们悔意的象征或展示？
Well, can I get personal for a second?
嗯，我能说点个人的吗？
I just was thinking about this in terms of engagement.
我刚才在想订婚这方面。
So why do people give a ring when they get engaged?
所以为什么人们订婚时要送戒指？
So I think it's because people like things that glitter, you know, it's like distract
所以我觉得是因为人们喜欢闪闪发光的东西，你知道，就像分散
the woman and she'll say yes.
女人的注意力，她就会说愿意。
And so it's the similar thing with with flowers and forgiveness.
所以这和送花与原谅是类似的事情。
You say, oh, gosh, these flowers are so beautiful.
你说，哦，天哪，这些花真漂亮。
Of course, I forgive you.
当然，我原谅你。
Oh, they're so pretty.
哦，它们真好看。
They smell so, you know, it's like it's like distraction from the matter at hand.
它们闻起来这么，你知道，就像分散对当前问题的注意力。
Right.
对。
Maybe that's it.
也许就是这样。
I know.
我知道。
If you disagree with me, please.
如果你不同意我，请说。
It was a very wise man who invented this.
发明这个的人非常聪明。
Absolutely.
绝对。
All right.
好了。
So if you have any questions, doubts or comments, please come to our website, EnglishPod.com
所以如果你有任何问题、疑问或评论，请访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com
and we'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
Bye.
再见。